[{"id": "596df9cdf0cc2631d16a3c65", "question": "In 1993, Billy Dean took his version of which 1977 pop hit by Dave Mason to #9 on the country charts?", "answer": "\"We Just Disagree\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cab", "question": "In Greek mythology, the hundred-eyed Argus was honored by Hera by being transformed into what bird?", "answer": "Peacock", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1f", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"The Color of Money\"?", "answer": "Pool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b699098e762b54eb9be9412", "question": "How is the number 20 written with Roman numerals?", "answer": "XX", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062b9fc9d816e292245c21", "question": "Who is credited with writing \"The Odyssey\" and \"The Iliad\"?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f74c4a9e54d890926f6ff", "question": "In June in Wyoming, it is illegal to take a picture of what?", "answer": "A rabbit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe735f1eec85e375820b256", "question": "What was the the name of the play President Lincoln was watching when John Wilkes Booth shot him?", "answer": "Our American Cousin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133994c", "question": "What actress replaced Farrah Fawcett on \"Charlie\u2019s Angels\" in 1977?", "answer": "Cheryl Ladd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067b9aff9c0647b50a8066", "question": "What smartglasses were you able to purchase on November 10 2016, from a proprietary vending machine?", "answer": "Spectacles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e77d06d333868d34d73e", "question": "At what time of year did the Celts believe the Sun stood still for 12 days?", "answer": "Winter solstice", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c07d", "question": "What is hippophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Horses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975f", "question": "What two murderesses does Billy Flynn represent in Chicago?", "answer": "Velma Kelly and Roxie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b660", "question": "What US auto maker produced a car called the Cirrus?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c25", "question": "Who wrote the book \"One Fish, Two Fish, Red Fish, Blue Fish\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590678e5ff9c0647b50a804d", "question": "What month, in 2016, did the World Trade Organization announce an outbreak of the Zika virus?", "answer": "January", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6ab5020565ad31a57c828", "question": "Who said, \"Pleasure is the bait of sin\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ca", "question": "Who sang the song \"Foolish Games\"?", "answer": "Jewel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae14", "question": "Montezuma was the emperor of which ancient society?", "answer": "Aztecs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e44", "question": "What two-word phrase is the first writing to appear in \"Charlotte's Web\"?", "answer": "Some pig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa31373838c5c8a417f1e", "question": "What kind of anthropology is also known as ethnology?", "answer": "Cultural anthropology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21e", "question": "What city was Indira Gandhi killed in?", "answer": "New Delhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6b70ffb6c85e9e634ff4a", "question": "Who composed and played the score for the film 1953 film \"Genevieve\"?", "answer": "Larry Adler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1ce3f7bd84c0ea43ad435", "question": "On which river does the capital of Canada lie?", "answer": "Ottawa River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b1be01dd7bf43be5e794", "question": "Which best describes an idea that\u2019s \"all sizzle and no steak\"?", "answer": "Not living up to expectations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133976a", "question": "What is the name of the clown in It?", "answer": "Pennywise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1c", "question": "What famed object from mythology did the Venus de Milo hold in her now-missing left hand?", "answer": "The golden apple of Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c567", "question": "What name is given to the device which consists of a frame with parallel wires carrying beads used for computation?", "answer": "Abacus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b3", "question": "Anthony Robert McMillan became famous as who?", "answer": "Robbie Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989a9bbcb8751d53e7d7601", "question": "What is the deadliest jellyfish in the world?", "answer": "Box Jellyfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b305", "question": "How did Ponce de Leon, Claudius, and Tycho Brahe all die?", "answer": "They were poisoned", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c727", "question": "What element\u2019s chemical symbol is the letter \"I\"?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0a", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Edge of Reason\"?", "answer": "Bridget Jones's Diary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab9", "question": "What gas is exhaled by humans?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b63ee662d71a53651004", "question": "In Herman Melville\u2019s novel \"Moby Dick\", who was the loyal, reasonable first mate?", "answer": "Starbuck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22b", "question": "Gandhi's famous march to Dandi in 1930 was an act to protest against Great Britain's tax on what?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc37f6de0eb824d4052ed", "question": "What U.S. state is the smallest by land area?", "answer": "Rhode Island -- At 1214 sq.mi., it is half the size of Miami-Dade County, FL (2431 sq. mi), but has nearly 400 miles of shoreline.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918e", "question": "Who is smarter than the average bear?", "answer": "Yogi Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394af", "question": "What was the name of the high school in which the TV show \"Room 222\" took place?", "answer": "Walt Whitman High", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc776ec223966ae8f888d", "question": "In TV, what is Leonard Hofstader's middle name?", "answer": "Leakey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea31ebff048f679a45aae6", "question": "What was invented by Chinese astronomer and mathematician Chang Heng?", "answer": "The first seismograph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a71c", "question": "Which US state shares a border with Ohio, Indiana and Wisconsin?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173d3644491cbd7c5a17ab", "question": "What was the original name for the Grammy Award(s)? ", "answer": "Gramophone Award ", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7ec1ab24f84e0b9f9ffe3", "question": "The Atomium is a famous tourist attraction in which city?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66c5da5bfecdd737e0893", "question": "What was the name of the world\u2019s last passenger pigeon?", "answer": "Martha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e78afe83fe1f2a824bd4", "question": "In medieval history, what was a \"schiltron\"?", "answer": "A battle formation that consisted of soldiers with long spears placed into circular, tightly packed formations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c744", "question": "What is the more common name for the bone called the furcula, found in birds?", "answer": "Wishbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4b", "question": "John Dillinger was gunned down by the FBI in front of what Chicago movie theater?", "answer": "Biograph", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3dd", "question": "Who did Arthur Bremer try to assassinate in 1972?", "answer": "George Wallace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a578", "question": "Providence is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba50", "question": "What basketball legend was born Ferdinand Lewis Alcindor?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded288ea2747c8aff16d3e", "question": "What year did Dwight D. Eisenhower publish his autobiography titled \"Crusade in Europe\"?", "answer": "1948", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf5", "question": "What year was actress Julia Roberts born?", "answer": "1967", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3b3", "question": "What color is the cross on the Swedish flag?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10b", "question": "Who was elected to the Senate seat vacated by New York Democrat Daniel Patrick Moynihan on January 3, 2001?", "answer": "Hillary Rodham Clinton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of North Carolina?", "answer": "Raleigh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15a", "question": "In what year was New York City divided into its boroughs?", "answer": "1898", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86d", "question": "Where in England is the Stonehenge monument located?", "answer": "Wiltshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba4c4874c93a3298b2148", "question": "What is the highest mountain in Wales?", "answer": "Mount Snowdon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a7", "question": "Of the seven colors of the rainbow which is the middle one?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab1c27baab681b0929219f", "question": "What car did Chevrolet design the Camaro to compete with in 1966?", "answer": "The Ford Mustang", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdd59e20499cffc60b8422b", "question": "What was the last Province to join Canada?", "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25a", "question": "What is 400 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "CD", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8cb3ec223966ae8f884d", "question": "\"Bootylicious\" has become an accepted word in the Oxford Dictionary thanks to a track of the same name by which artist(s)?", "answer": "Destiny's Child", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a589", "question": "Which present day US state did Ponce De Leon explore?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b211", "question": "Who was assassinated by Gavrilo Princip?", "answer": "Archduke Ferdinand", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddc5e6ce05a3942286d9b", "question": "Which film included the real 1946 Macy\u2019s Thanksgiving Day Parade?", "answer": "\"Miracle on 34th Street\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91b", "question": "What is the temperature, at which dew forms, called?", "answer": "Dew point", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa11", "question": "Into what sea does the Elbe River flow?", "answer": "North Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c089", "question": "Wanamaker's of Philadelphia first US store to install what in 1878?", "answer": "Electric illumination", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8c", "question": "When did Arizona and New Mexico become states?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76861eec85e375820b2a0", "question": "What is the tallest peak in Colorado?", "answer": "Mt. Elbert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd3b97e83c707845b2154", "question": "How many noble houses of Westeros are there in \"Game of Thrones\"?", "answer": "Nine (Arryn, Baratheon, Greyjoy, Lannister, Martell, Stark, Targaryen, Tully and Tyrell)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339199", "question": "What instrument does Meg White play in the band White Stripes?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0f0", "question": "Which historic figure is famous for having said, \"Give Me Liberty or Give Me Death\"?", "answer": "Patrick Henry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3f7eff048f679a45ab5f", "question": "Which animal product does an ovo-vegetarian eat?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c1", "question": "What does Ambidextrous mean?", "answer": "Equally skilled with both hands", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae13", "question": "In which decade was the Berlin Wall erected?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c625", "question": "How many stars does Aries consist of?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8efe901dd7bf43be5e7f6", "question": "What is the official name for a blob of toothpaste on a toothbrush?", "answer": "Nurdle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c56", "question": "What was the name of Whitney Houston's 1985 debut album?", "answer": "Whitney Houston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974a", "question": "Who was the first Ink Master contestant to compete in 2 seasons?", "answer": "Tatu Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000f1159a72b906b34e3d01", "question": "What name is given to a cockerel that has been castrated, and often fattened, to increase the quality of its meat?", "answer": "Capon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be18", "question": "Which modern instrument was called the sackbut until the nineteenth century?", "answer": "The trombone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc6", "question": "What are the primary ingredients for the dish Cullen Skink?", "answer": "Fish, potatoes and onions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff66e3852a821ff76ae8b1a", "question": "What do you eat when you accept that you're wrong about something?", "answer": "\"Crow\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0f42469bb8041d07a066", "question": "Which animal was part of the Gloria Vanderbilt jeans logo?", "answer": "Swan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339622", "question": "Leonardo DiCaprio played which Shakespearian character in a 1996 movie?", "answer": "Romeo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90cfc152800b05cac20f0b", "question": "What is the only African nation with Spanish as the official language?", "answer": "Equatorial Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b371481c3f17ccc40c8e1e", "question": "Approximately how much more beer would you get in a pint served in the UK compared to one served in the US?", "answer": "95 mL", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f0e", "question": "Filmmaker Duncan Jones is the son of which British Glam Rock legend?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc1100469bb8041d07a072", "question": "What is the correct plural of Keeshond?", "answer": "Keeshonden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b69", "question": "What was the first sports-themed movie to win the Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Rocky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf8", "question": "What J.D. Salinger character never found out where the ducks in Central Park go during the winter?", "answer": "Holden Caulfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b201", "question": "What ship was commanded by William Bligh?", "answer": "Bounty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a9f", "question": "John Reed's book \"Ten Days That Shook the World\" was an eyewitness account of which event?", "answer": "The Russian Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015fb83fe83fe1f2a824c39", "question": "St. Patrick wrote in his Declaration that when he was 16 years what happened?", "answer": "According to his own writings, St. Patrick said he was was captured by Irish pirates when he was 16 years old.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3e", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"The River Bank\"?", "answer": "The Wind in the Willows", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee2", "question": "What position was first held by Muhammad Naguib?", "answer": "President of Egypt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bb64fb6c85e9e634ff54", "question": "Whose fifth album was called \"Different Class\"?", "answer": "Pulp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f0", "question": "Which artist painted \"American Gothic\"?", "answer": "Grant Wood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff145dbb0ee8c595b6d39bc", "question": "The pen name of which American writer means \"two fathoms deep\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa9456ce05a3942286ede", "question": "Where was Babe Ruth born?", "answer": "Baltimore", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3ee638b5801b8f54a7fb7", "question": "Which was the last major offensive operation undertaken by elite German paratroopers in World War II?", "answer": "Attack against Crete", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01c", "question": "What U.S. President declared \"The ballot is stronger than the bullet\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed3", "question": "What game did Charles Darrow based upon the \"The Landlord's Game\"?", "answer": "Monopoly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a17", "question": "Jamie Somers became \"The Bionic Woman\" following emergency surgery after what type of accident?", "answer": "Parachuting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f1affe83fe1f2a824c17", "question": "When was the first time that the city of Chicago dyed the famous Chicago River green in commemoration of St. Patrick's Day?", "answer": "1962", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a270", "question": "Who was the female lead in the 1967 film \"Barefoot in the Park\"?", "answer": "Jane Fonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa5886ce05a3942286ec2", "question": "What classic music was used in the television series \"The Lone Ranger\"?", "answer": "March of the Swiss Soldiers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5af", "question": "What are Catalonia, Andalusia, Cantabria, Galicia?", "answer": "Regions in Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b9", "question": "What was the first music video that aired on MTV in 1981?", "answer": "Video Killed the Radio Star", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb088cccf631c2414a13b5c", "question": "Which house only became one of the Great Houses of Westeros after Aegon Targaryen\u2019s invasion?", "answer": "House Tyrell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd93", "question": "Who merged with the struggling Cleveland Barons in 1978?", "answer": "The Minnesota North Stars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a941", "question": "What peninsula is held together, at its narrowest point, by the Isthmus of Kra?", "answer": "The Malay Peninsula", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea49c1ff048f679a45abbb", "question": "What powdery substance contains the male sex cells of a flower?", "answer": "Pollen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398de", "question": "What TV series detective was played by Peter Falk?", "answer": "Columbo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d54", "question": "What year saw the release of the first Harry Potter book?", "answer": "1997", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c363", "question": "What part of the body does an orthopedic doctor treat?", "answer": "Bones", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd50", "question": "The Fields Medal is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Mathematics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c267", "question": "What is the world's fastest dog?", "answer": "The greyhound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc8a0ec223966ae8f8891", "question": "Pro golfers rack up points as they compete for what corporate-sponsored cup that was first awarded in 2007?", "answer": "The FedEx Cup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339482", "question": "Who directed the 1969 movie \"The Wild Bunch\"?", "answer": "Sam Peckinpah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04e", "question": "What is the only superhero film of the 1970s that earned enough at the box office to be a top ten film for that decade?", "answer": "Superman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bee", "question": "What year did singer Cherilyn Sarkisian La Piere Bono Allman legally change her name to just Cher?", "answer": "1978", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b567", "question": "How high is a soccer goal?", "answer": "8 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d67", "question": "Who played the role of TV's C. J. Parker?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc2", "question": "What TV judge wrote the book \"Don't Pee on My Leg and Tell Me It's Raining\"?", "answer": "Judge Judy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc1", "question": "What onetime NBA Finals MVP was the last owner of the CBA before its 2001 bankruptcy?", "answer": "Isiah Thomas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb7827e83c707845b2130", "question": "What is the hybrid offspring of a llama and camel called?", "answer": "Cama", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb4", "question": "What violinist performed the title character's solos in the film \"Fiddler on the Roof\"?", "answer": "Isaac Stern", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd665bca5bfecdd737e0862", "question": "How long ago did mammoths go extinct?", "answer": "4000 years ago", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be73", "question": "What is LP Field also known as?", "answer": "The Woodshed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb00665ff7d326b622a5f", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69cdd20565ad31a57c770", "question": "What was the name of the Mayflower's sister ship?", "answer": "Speedwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefd", "question": "What did explorer Robert Peary attempt to reach in 1909?", "answer": "The North Pole", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a486", "question": "Mount Etna is located on which island?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be07", "question": "Frank Sinatra was buried with a bottle of what whiskey?", "answer": "Jack Daniel's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f6", "question": "Which character in the Simpsons was kicked out of the barbershop quartet, \"The Be Sharps\"?", "answer": "Chief Wiggum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35c", "question": "What is British politician William Hague's middle name?", "answer": "Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9e0d8e748bb36357acdf0", "question": "In the film \"Walk the Line\" who played June Carter Cash?", "answer": "Reese Witherspoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b587", "question": "When was Gatorade first introduced?", "answer": "1965", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010cab30775fa611bce67fd", "question": "What do the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame and the Louvre have in common?", "answer": "A design by the same architect -- I.M. Pei provided the design for the entrances to both museums.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c34c5815febcc896f9255", "question": "Which is the Earth's largest continent?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62c", "question": "Which planet is referred to as the planet of oceans?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b48f849076251badbeaa9", "question": "Who won the first Nobel Prize for Medicine?", "answer": "Emil von Behring -- He discovered a diphtheria antitoxin.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c483", "question": "In what decade was the very first test-tube baby born?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a4", "question": "Which US state was established by William Penn in 1681?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927c", "question": "What are the only 100% guarantees of safety in the TV show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Head of Household and Veto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe765e6eec85e375820b279", "question": "What US state's flag has different images on the front and back?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc46f6de0eb824d4052f3", "question": "Which African country was formerly known as Abyssinia?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a1a42a12f2a7826b9b872d", "question": "What is a female goat called?", "answer": "A Nanny", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69e8720565ad31a57c785", "question": "What region of Belgium was the Battle of the Bulge fought during World War II?", "answer": "Ardennes Forrest", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a114", "question": "What was the name of Mulder and Scully's supervisor on the TV show \"The X-Files\"?", "answer": "Walter Skinner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df2", "question": "What 1990 dance craze gave the Digital Underground their biggest hit?", "answer": "The Humpty Hump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e5f11add274615ecf51453a", "question": "In what country was the worlds first ice hotel built?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3d", "question": "Which archaeologist discovered King Tut's tomb in 1922?", "answer": "Howard Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ce", "question": "What TV spy often tried to pass himself off as a salesman for the Pontiac Greeting Card Company?", "answer": "Maxwell Smart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff20e9231a458464a93c425", "question": "Iron Man's \"Veronica\" was built to contain whom?", "answer": "The Hulk", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7e", "question": "Baku is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Azerbaijan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b840", "question": "In which sport would you be judged on your pike or your jack knife?", "answer": "Diving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cfcfbb53d1af658864f6", "question": "What is the curved part of the candy cane known as?", "answer": "The warble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989a89acb8751d53e7d75fb", "question": "Who won the fourth Super Bowl?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a85", "question": "Who flew from England to America in a giant peach carried by seagulls?", "answer": "James", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d0662596a59cbdfbd37b", "question": "Who said, \"Whenever I hear anyone arguing for slavery, I feel a strong impulse to see it tried on him personally\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3b", "question": "In 1947, what pilot first broke the supersonic barrier?", "answer": "Chuck Yeager", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071cb03745b36be73039cf", "question": "In what present-day country was the first space launch facility located?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133909b", "question": "In Greek mythology, what is Demeter the goddess of what?", "answer": "Harvest and agriculture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c52d", "question": "What bird can swim but cannot fly?", "answer": "The Penguin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfbb", "question": "March, April and May are the only months that have what?", "answer": "Anagrams - Charm, Ripal, Yam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca1", "question": "Who was the principal of Riverdale High School in the \"Archie\" comics?", "answer": "Mr. Weatherbee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a89c", "question": "What is Greenland called by its Inuit native residents?", "answer": "Kaallalit Nunaat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65d511f3c0ead6880d61a", "question": "The Haloid Company is the original name of what company?", "answer": "Xerox", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e3", "question": "What was the first name of Martin Short's character on his TV show \"Primetime Glick\"?", "answer": "Jiminy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ecf", "question": "Whose last book was \"Oh, the Places You'll Go\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e5", "question": "Who directed the film \"Serpico\"?", "answer": "Sidney Lumet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a899c2e60d398dc9cf7a6a5", "question": "Vesta is the Roman goddess of what?", "answer": "Hearth, home and family", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cde", "question": "What does Marvel Comics character Howard the Duck often have in his mouth?", "answer": "A cigar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff3c2eb4f032c0db195b487", "question": "What mathematician spent his life calculating the value of pi to 707 decimal places?", "answer": "William Shanks", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff20e9d31a458464a93c426", "question": "What was Peter Parker's day job?", "answer": "Photographer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede1b36ce05a3942286dc4", "question": "What is Michael J. Fox's middle name?", "answer": "Andrew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99b3e21a8909e5c332d29", "question": "Who played the main female character in the 1939 film \"Destry Rides Again\"?", "answer": "Marlene Dietrich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a73e", "question": "Oneida Lake is located in which US state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba37d874c93a3298b213c", "question": "What additional part does someone with Polyorhidism have?", "answer": "Extra testicle(s)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c9", "question": "Who was the last European head of state to be executed after being removed from power?", "answer": "Nicolae Ceausescu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b3", "question": "What occurs when the Sun and the Moon are in conjunction as viewed from Earth?", "answer": "A solar eclipse", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6996320565ad31a57c745", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the father of Arphaxad?", "answer": "Shem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb668f5dad637d903c8838", "question": "The Maluku islands (informally known as the Spice Islands) belong to which country?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ef", "question": "Which classic science fiction author wrote \"The End of Eternity\", \"Pebble in the Sky\", and \"The Caves of Steel\"?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396cf", "question": "Who is the teacher of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles?", "answer": "Master Splinter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e0b", "question": "The Don McLean song that begins \"Starry starry night\" is actually named for what painter?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66ca5a5bfecdd737e0896", "question": "Where did the concept of \"rolling out the red carpet\" originate?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b6", "question": "Whose still-life painting, \"Rideau Cruchon et Compotier\", sold for $60.5 million in 1999?", "answer": "Paul Cezanne's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6f", "question": "Edam cheese comes from what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b433", "question": "What year did the Mau Mau Uprising end?", "answer": "1960", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18a", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Nine Tonight\"?", "answer": "Bob Seger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a5", "question": "The 1962 movie \"Lawrence of Arabia\" was based on the real-life exploits of whom?", "answer": "T.E. Lawrence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002431a4be4723ccac22190", "question": "How is the author Eric Arthur Blair better know?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398fd", "question": "On July 10, 1975, Cher filed for divorce from what musician?", "answer": "Gregg Allman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c382", "question": "What poisonous spider can be identified by a small red hourglass-shaped marking on the underside of its body?", "answer": "Black widow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c28", "question": "Who wrote \"Little House in the Big Woods\"?", "answer": "Laura Ingalls Wilder", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590682b1ff9c0647b50a809f", "question": "What is the name of the little boy who disappeared in the beginning of the \"Stranger Things\" Netflix series?", "answer": "Will Byers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76bb2eec85e375820b2c7", "question": "Where can you golf the world\u2019s highest elevation championship course?", "answer": "La Paz Golf Club, Bolivia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b33", "question": "What 1980s movie soundtrack gave us the #1 hit by the band Berlin titled \"Take My Breath Away\"?", "answer": "Top Gun", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea43beff048f679a45ab87", "question": "What enzyme is responsible for breaking down starches?", "answer": "Amylase", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ce", "question": "In the Southern Hemisphere, summer begins in what month?", "answer": "December", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ae", "question": "How many ghosts appear to Scrooge in Dicken's \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59675bac2b59efe0e9417e90", "question": "Whose \"Hicktown\" country music singer first hit single debuted on the radio in 2005?", "answer": "Jason Aldean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fca", "question": "Which Canadian province is the setting for the novel \"Anne of Green Gables\"?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be5806d5415ba52ed6f0ab4", "question": "Saint Stephen's Day is better known as what?", "answer": "Boxing day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81b7dd0de9af39e9d4679", "question": "Who was the first woman to run for President of the U.S.?", "answer": "Victoria Woodhull", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be72", "question": "What is the Darlington Raceway also known as?", "answer": "The Track Too Tough to Tame", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f8", "question": "Which group had albums called \"Fireball\" and \"Machine Head\"?", "answer": "Deep Purple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adca", "question": "Which treaty organisation was set up as a counterpart to NATO?", "answer": "Warsaw Pact", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cabdbb53d1af658864d2", "question": "On what short story was the 1946 film \"It\u2019s a Wonderful Life\" based on?", "answer": "The Greatest Gift", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00c", "question": "In the tech field, what does AMD stand for?", "answer": "Advanced Micro Devices", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029fbecad1ec93f27df764", "question": "Who was Strongbow cider named after?", "answer": "Richard de Clare", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be09", "question": "What NFL team replaced its AFL-era horse logo with a bolt of lightning?", "answer": "The San Diego Chargers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937eaa908d98002fdd633a5", "question": "Which country owns Easter Island?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b129", "question": "What was known as the Lady of the Lamp?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590722593745b36be73039fe", "question": "According to Futurama, what holiday is celebrated on December 25th in the year 3,000?", "answer": "Xmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c234", "question": "What do Teal Pumpkins represent to Trick or Treaters?", "answer": "Non-Food Treats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b316", "question": "On April 11, 1990, California Angel Mike Witt combined with which starter to pitch a no-hit victory?", "answer": "Mark Langston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a39d", "question": "What European capital celebrated its 2,000th anniversary in 1951?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3d", "question": "What were the first modern Olympic pole vaulters' poles made of?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a735", "question": "What city's buildings include the John Hancock Center and the Amoco Building?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb68cb5dad637d903c8844", "question": "The unofficial Wei\u00dfwurst\u00e4quator, or \"white sausage equator\", separates Bavaria and the south from the rest of which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f3", "question": "What is the name the Australian film based on the life of pianist David Helfgott?", "answer": "Shine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d0062596a59cbdfbd376", "question": "Who said, \"Call no man unhappy until he is married\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c9640775fa611bce67eb", "question": "What is the name of an architectural certification in green design?", "answer": "LEED certification -- It is a verification that the design is resource-efficient, high-performing, healthy, and cost-effective.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523c2b736d4be723796b35", "question": "Which Quebec city does Canada\u2019s capital border?", "answer": "Gatineau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067ed5ff9c0647b50a807f", "question": "To what age did the US state of Hawaii change the legal smoking age on January 1, 2016?", "answer": "21", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078b710eee65b76b9f2668", "question": "What name was given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfe229dc5ec6cd98a8328", "question": "Who is the protagonist of \"The Hunger Games\"?", "answer": "Katniss Everdeen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8acec01dd7bf43be5e772", "question": "When primary colors are mixed together, they create what?", "answer": "Secondary colors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008de2df4f3bc4a292f8628", "question": "Who stated, \"Injustice anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere\".", "answer": "Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. (He wrote it in his famous open letter known as \"Letter from Birmingham Jail\".)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25a53b63e5727cf5a4852", "question": "Who sang the songs \"Bump n' Grind\" and \"She's Got That Vibe\"?", "answer": "R Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399de", "question": "Who was the only one of the six main characters on \"Friends\" to not get married at any time on the show?", "answer": "Joey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81b63d0de9af39e9d4678", "question": "Where did the deadliest avalanche occur?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338988", "question": "What subject does Miss Sherman teach in the musical \"Fame\"?", "answer": "English", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea48c0ff048f679a45abb3", "question": "Which electronic component can be classified as NPN or PNP?", "answer": "Transistor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c9", "question": "What does the \"64\" in \"Commodore 64\" mean?", "answer": "Kilobytes of memory", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389cb", "question": "What are the six characters in the title of Luigi Pirandello's play i search of?", "answer": "An author", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ba", "question": "What actor played the role of Officer Don Orville in the TV show \"Third Rock From The Sun\"?", "answer": "Wayne Knight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590722383745b36be73039fd", "question": "What international company is said to have influenced the image of the modern-day Santa Claus?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af9858caeb0982ee455954e", "question": "Which physical force is the only one that is always attractive, never repulsive?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb7", "question": "What is the largest football stadium in Brazil?", "answer": "The Maracana stadium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008ee5cf842fa4c4ba96b6", "question": "What were \"Jelly Babies\" renamed to in 1918 to mark the end of World War I?", "answer": "Peace Babies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6f", "question": "What was Rod Stewart's first #1 song?", "answer": "Maggie May", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d2", "question": "\"The Running of the Bulls\" event is held in what Spanish city?", "answer": "Pamplona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a77020565ad31a57c7e8", "question": "Which Wild West figure was nicknamed \"little sure-shot\"?", "answer": "Annie Oakley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac1d", "question": "Paramaribo is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af1", "question": "What sporting competition was the focus of the 2007 film \"Balls of Fury\"?", "answer": "Ping Pong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7c", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Doris Mann in the novel \"Postcards from the Edge\"?", "answer": "Debbie Reynolds", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339995", "question": "What was the name of He-Man's main nemesis on \"He-Man and the Masters of the Universe\"?", "answer": "Skeletor", "category": "entertainment"}]